

# Soma Utsumi

# Software Engineer, Site Reliability Engineer

Tokyo, Japan

# **SUMMARY**

I'm a founding member of Industry Technology Inc, where I serve as CTO. Here I'm driving the development of the SaaS product and providing technical leadership.

I have also served as a SRE on the side, helping to solve business and technical problems from multiple perspectives.

### **SKILLS**

# SRE

- SLI/SLO Design
- Postmortem
- · Capacity Planning
- Security
- Observability
- Kubernetes
- Datadog

#### Platform Engineering

- Architectural Design
- Monitoring
- Cost Management
- CI/CD
- Developer Experience
- Terraform

#### Cloud

- GCP
- AWS

#### Backend

- Go
- gRPC
- Connect
- GraphQLMusCol
- MySQL
- PostgreSQL

# **LANGUAGES**

- Japanese(Native)
- English(Professional working)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2023-11 - Side, SRE in SRE desk

Present enechain Corporation

**Duties** 

Security

• Platform Engineering

Site Reliability

2023-08 - Side, MLOps Engineer in LLM STUDIO

Present Algomatic Inc.

**Duties** 

• Building learning infrastructures for LLM

- Building inference servers for LLM
- Building application infrastructures for products

2019-04 - **Co-founder,CTO** 

Present Industry Technology Inc.

**Duties** 

• Development of enterprise SaaS for building management companies

- Architecture Design
- Spec Refinement
- · Tech Strategy
- Recruiting

2018-04 - Data Analyst, Digital Marketer

2019-06 Gunosy Inc.

**Duties** 

- Planning A/B tests
- Analyzing the user data

2018-01 - Intern, Backend Engineer

2018-03 ZUU Co.,Ltd.

**Duties** 

• Development of the internal system

# **EDUCATION**

2014 - 2018 Bachelor of Engineering

The University of Tokyo

Design of a preoperative evaluation system for elderly patients using a

generalized linear model

# **DETAILED RESUME**

https://github.com/soma00333/resume/blob/main/README.md